guys today we're not just planning for a
future we're stepping into a world where
peace of mind and security are within
our reach with credential come along as
I take you on a journey on how they make
it
[Music]
happen hi guys welcome to Lisa kusima
Channel Hey guys today I'm here with the
CEO credential we've had a talk about
you know planning for your future and I
thought why not come here at credential
so they can tell us more about their
offering um welcome to the channel T
thank you liisa yes I'm happy to have
you and as we go deep into the topic um
as a family woman myself I'm a wife I'm
a mom of three kids and you know I know
about insurance but many people do not
know what are some of those things you'd
like to tell maybe a family out there
when it comes to choosing a policy or
getting getting Insurance why they
should get that insurance policy why get
an insurance policy now it's interesting
to know that in our part of the world um
insurance is one of the last things
people think about I forever remember an
experience when um I sold to an
organization one of the African
countries I worked in and we had experts
in the on the amongst the management and
they listened to the whole presentation
and what actually shocked that people
were asking
questions and they said in Europe where
we come from you get your first paycheck
you pay your tax you pay your your your
Social Security the next thing you think
about is to own a life insurance policy
because asserting as you start work
you're going to end work someday and
life insurance policies allow you to
create assets by the payment of the
first premium yeah there two things that
happen to you in life things that you
can't address with one salary
payment um planning to have an asset mhm
if you had some somebody hand to you 50
million Shillings today yeah you'd be
extremely excited wouldn't you be
excited now assume that you chose to set
aside 300,000 Shillings each month every
year 3.6 million M over 10 years that's
36 million over 15 years that would be
over 50 million Shillings yeah where
were he 15 years
ago and what did you do with the last
300,000 Shillings on mobile money wallet
cfee Jas
they would be happy if they getting all
that money from you but the but the
point is that's exactly the point money
runs through our accounts the element of
compulsion is not there we are not able
to save and day in day out the
opportunity to create this asset is
passing by yeah but life insurance
policy get you the opportunity to be
able to do this once you tell the bank
or the 26 of every month take the money
from my account they will take the money
from your account and remit it to us and
we build an asset for you on the other
hand if you take a life insurance policy
to day and we issue it for the 1st of
January and touch with anything happens
to you on the 2nd of January yeah the
insurance company is bound by the
contract to pay the benefits of that
policy and sometimes you take a 300,000
policy the benefit is 50 million you die
on the third day we pay 50 million to
your family so the payment of One
Premium creates an asset which is
different from you trying to invest and
save so we say your Investment Portfolio
is complemented by your life insurance
products whil takes a long time to build
an investment asset a life insurance
policy creates the asset the first day
your premium is paid yeah and that's
great the second thing is there are
things that happen in life that you
don't plan
for In-laws parents passing away we
don't want to hear that conversation
because we're talking about people who
are close to us emotional connection we
don't want to think about a day they
would pass culturally we don't want to
tell our parents I'm planning for your
death no but I've been here in this
country for a while now first thing that
happens when somebody passes we set up a
contributions page and everybody is
contributing yes which is subject to
people's feelings in their pockets at
that time to contribute to you but if
you buy a FAL product A Farewell plan
and you say if my parent passes our
touch would give me 10 million Shillings
the woman death occurs you are due a
payout of 10 million shillings to help
you organize the funeral and give them a
decent and a beffiting burier which you
never get a chance to do twice in your
life you only get to do for perod true
that's why you need to get a life
insurance policy amazing especially me
being a family person I think about it
um if my spouse passes on you know I
don't want to struggle and have the
income has definitely gone has reduced
and now I'm trying as a single M trying
to support the children you know you so
we do have policies called in income
replacement policies um where you or
your spouse will determine that this is
my annual salary yeah and I can take
twice or three times my annual salary M
on a on a 10 product and say look for
the next 10 15 years if anything happens
to me pay three times my Ann salary to
my spouse because she would need to
cover for the income that is lost
because I have left yeah and that income
replacement means a lot it means that
the kids education continues the home
rental continues the standard of living
can be retained for as long as it takes
for you to bounce back you know try to
close the gap and that's what insurance
policies are for to cater for the
unexpected yeah the uncertain timing of
those bad events in life which we cannot
determine but we know they will happen
we all prefer to go on retirement and
die peacefully yeah everybody wishes for
that but not everybody gets that yeah um
we have other policies that take care of
individuals if they diagnosed with
critical illness and as much as we don't
want that to happen in this part of the
developing world where sugar intake is
High um usage of oil in cooking is high
cholesterol levels and diabetes are a
big issue yeah um alcohol consumption is
a big thing all these find a way of
affecting our hearts our kidneys um and
our liver Li and what it does is that
when anybody unfortunately gets into
that position we have insurance policies
that
pay significant amount of money of
course determined by the one who bought
it to help them cater for the treatment
um stroke heart disease
um heart attacks um kidney failure
things that are very expensive to treat
you get a certain payout up front toble
to take care of the bills that will come
out out of that um prostate cancer you
know um they might seem farfetched to
individuals until you are found in that
position and then you would appreciate
that you have a cover that pays out a
significant amount of money um to you in
that instance and I've seen people
receive payouts in the excess of 100 200
250 million Shillings in those
circumstances because they bought a
policy like that yours might not be 100
or 20 million but it's 50 or 70 million
and you need to pay your bills that's
buying you extra life and getting you
the chance to fix your life and live and
live properly and insurance policies do
this for you some cover is better than
no cover at all yeah amazing so there
are people out there who think insurance
is only for the wealthy like you guys
have money to spare that's why you're
putting it out there to say remember
what I said yeah by the payment of One
Premium you create an asset yeah um
and I would say insurance is for those
of us who can't afford not to be without
one what do I mean by that if I give you
like I said if I give you 50 million
Shillings You' find something to do with
it if you're rich and you have 500
million shs that 50 million Shillings
will be well okay petty cash but if you
don't have then you need did more than
anybody else and that's the key um so
those of us who don't have the money it
is for us that we use this to create
that asset and if at 25 you start by
paying 300,000 Shillings a month and by
the time you turn 40 somebody hands you
a 50 million Shilling check to start the
next phase of your life with imagine
what it could do just investing that 50
million Shillings gives you an
additional 5 million Shillings each year
yeah either for your pocket or to add
and compound and invest Again by time
you turn 60 that's a lot of money so
what those of us who don't have the
money don't realize is even though we
don't have money we have time as an
asset and use time and your discipline
to create an asset for yourself that
changes the course of your life in the
future I love it guys I hope you're
taking notes and how is credential
ensuring that it's affordable accessible
and can reach like everyone can access
it so for every policy that we
distribute there are there's a policy
for every pocket you determine how much
you want to pay yeah and then um we walk
the agent will work walk you through
what bank Arrangements you need to do um
and give you a cover that suits you so
for the farewell cover the pral cover
you would see that there are different
levels that you can choose in terms of
who you're covering how much money you
want check what use your pocket and then
you sign on for the educational plan
same approach yeah and least that for
yourself you can have a plan dedicated
to each child you want to ensure they go
to Harvard yeah how old are they now 6 4
1 so so 18 years from now yeah you know
the one who's one year old will be
getting ready for for
University that's a 36 million Shilling
sitting down right there so you can sign
one for each child and keep them as
beneficiaries so that's one way to look
at
what you can afford or the purpose for
which you're taking it for the children
and the good thing is as your income
increases you can also increase the
amount of money you put aside and you
create a very good future for yourself
and for your kids amazing thank you so
much for being here I think we have
covered so many things on here please
now we're going to talk to the people
you talked about you talk about agent
let's talk to them and hear more about
how prenal is making there are Gallant
soldiers who make sure there happens
they are the best people to talk to they
trade financial advisers they will talk
to you advise you and give you the right
policy that you need
[Music]
amazing Hi D hey how are you you great
thank you so they say that financial
advisors like yourself are the first
point of contact
with clients is that true yes it is I'll
just introduce myself my name is Abida
I'm an independent financial advisor and
a lifestyle protector at credential and
I'd like to say that I give people Peace
of Mind wow if you want peace yeah she's
your person so I've heard that
credential is celebrating 175 years yes
is there any key event or Landmark event
that has happened throughout history
that presential can you know a test too
okay I'm not that old first of all I'm
not that old I was not there then but I
must say there have been so many events
that credential has has been able to do
claims you know we've been existent
since um 1848 which actually makes us
175 years wow we we paid several claims
when we look at the Titanic we look at
the Spanish flu but the one thing I'll
talk about is the Titanic not because I
love the movie everyone loves the
Titanic anyway Rose and Jack exactly but
we were able to pay 292 to members that
sun on ship so for me what that tells me
is that you can trust them cuz they've
been here yes for a while yeah yes and
we're here to stay and you're here to
stay amazing all right so as you
interface with different clients as a
financial advisor we know there are lots
of policies out there how do you assess
that this policy is good for me maybe as
a mom as a wife as you know an
individual Etc how do you do that first
of all actually there's and that's where
the confusion comes there is so much
information is at our disposal and
there's a lot of confusion on what
should I take who should I invest what
class of what class of asset should I
invest in but ideally when we meet a
prospect the first point of of course is
the relationship M you get to sit down
have a conversation an inperson
conversation of course understand first
of all where are they meeting you why
did they give you that appointment in
the first place that means there is a
need you need to assertain the need and
by ascertaining the need there's going
to be back and forth questions trigger
questions you need to figure out at what
point of at what point in their life the
stage at which they are are they married
have they just started their first job
are they transitioning do they have
children is it a blended family is it a
dual family is it a singular family are
they at a point of
retirement but do they have multiple
channels of income age is another Factor
disposable income is another Factor
because you might be speaking to people
but if they do not have a disposable
that can enable them build their
portfolio then you're not scking to
their paid points you need to understand
what are their financial goals where do
they see themselves in the short term in
the long term in the medium term or even
in the interim term because most of us
are saying the future but do you realize
I'm a mother I speak from my own
perspective cuz that's this is the
journey that I walk I walk from a
journey of failure a journey of having
no liquidity a journey of being asset
rich and liquid poor so you need to
empathize and have an understanding
where they at where are the loopholes
where are the gaps that we need to fill
in yeah we may have all these things
we're going to through so much technical
Juggy on these Financial classes and
instruments but the thing is what is
your relationship with money when we
ascertain those things your age where
you're at in the cycle of life we have
what we call the 28,000 rule that we'll
talk about later at every stage of your
life what are the things that you should
have done or what are the things that
the necessary things need to partake in
in order to have a fulfilled or a
balanced portfolio or have Financial
Independence so we're talking age yeah
what stage in life are you at are you
married are you single are you divorced
but even with that we plan because when
one is divorced there are certain assets
that will have to be split and and
things are not the same anymore and um
we talked about risk appetite we talked
about how our incomes children exactly
and uh there's so much there's so much
more we can we can take the whole day
and the cows will come home any but
bottom line is at least there those
basic core things that we need to look
up for whenever we're having a
conversation with our prospects okay so
I know prenal has a number of them are
able to just give us a few of those
policies that people need to take out or
need to be aware of okay uh first of all
we need need to know that we tailor make
or we curate policies depending on one's
need yeah the I there's no one size that
fits all but there are certain policies
that have have um have been quite
popular in the marketplace every Market
in in the UK the policies are different
West Africa the need is different the
policies are different in Uganda our
policies are different but I'd like to
say we had a flagship product called the
edgy save it was a it is is still kick
it is it is it is the Holy Grail it is
the Holy Grail of every parent who wants
to save towards education for their
children yeah and even those who may not
have children and are planning to have
children that would be a great policy
why is it a great policy most of the
times we are we you know we're parents
and when we see the bank slip you pay
sometimes we're even adulting we have
not ascertained how much will we need
for our child to finish in University or
high school till we have a conversation
with um a financial advisor or a risk
advisor so these policies enable you to
say now I have a child for example if
you have a child who is going to a
national school let's say paying 3
million Shillings per time in a year
they would have paid about 9 million
Shillings they're going to be in school
for the next 7 years going to high
school they'll be going to high school
when they're 13 so what we do is how do
we guarantee you that volume cuz if you
say we're doing uh 9 million * 7 you get
that number and we guarantee that value
not after 7 years but immediately so at
a at a case point that a risk
occurs the family the child the child's
education will not yeah be mhm they will
they will not they will not have a
struggle they not they will have no
issues so that money that payout is used
is given to the family for continuity of
the education and not only that we also
do a payout at a point of maturity so
it's one of those policies that actually
pay out
150% at a point of risk amazing now
people have um a Mis A misconception and
say but if a risk does not occur cuz
whenever people look at Insurance
they're thinking they only pay when I
die yeah no no no no no and I don't want
to die exactly yeah and we do not also
want to fake death if you know what I
mean yes but but what we do we have
these policies are called endowment
policies an endowment policy is such
that you're able to pay your premiums at
a point that a risk occurs we pay at a
point that a risk does not occur we
still are able to pay with interest
acred and guess what taxfree tell me any
business Institute person who would want
to pay for their financial instrument
with a tax implication no the rich are
rich because they transfer risk the rich
are rich because of the fact that they
know how to work
around Taxation and life Assurance or
protection policies are the only
financial instrument that do not have a
tax
application then of course the other
policies we we realized during U covid
there was an issue with liquidity and
most people did not have emergency funds
that's true so we had to curate policies
whereby said how is it how are people
able to have policies where they can be
able to
liquidate of the investment so we have
not only do we have protection we are
protecting against things like critical
illness there is death there's total
permanent disability but guess what we
also have another arm or another portion
which is investment which acrs actually
over 10% without taxation it's like
having it's like having what we call a
unit trust it's a hybrid of a unit Trust
prot you have it all so as you're being
protected your money is passively
working for you yes so you can actually
be able to liquidate off your investment
policy if you have an issue instead of
going to a money lender you put your log
book you're selling your 50 by 100
because it's a f you know what I mean so
just go get your go to operations or
just write to operations claim and then
liquidate off your invest folio and
utilize it to solve your problem and
your policy keeps running amazing so we
have so many but these two have uh have
been a great product for our Market yes
so we've created something that has that
flexibility wow yes amazing yes so as we
talk about life insurance we know it's
touchy it's a touchy subject um first of
all people do not understand it some may
think you know death ITC and their
Jitter what strategies do you use when
speaking to prospects to help them
understand this life insurance is
actually for their
benefit you know first of all Muslim mhm
Muslims don't believe in life Assurance
it is actually Haram certain cultures
don't believe in Insurance because it's
it's like you're jinxing if you know
what that's it yeah the culture the
culture as it might even start like what
are you trying to do here you know but
the truth of the matter is things have
changed
people are more exposed these things are
happening this things death is around us
uh I believe most of us have had friends
who have passed on families who have
passed on and you can see the financial
toll it takes on a family it's it's it's
it's it's ridiculous you find families
have to dispose of their properties you
find that they have to sell off their
assets then of course the issues for
aing Legacy the issues pertaining the
proit law imagine a family is mourning
and they thinking what next lawyers
their legalities involved because
they've not put their things in order
they've not planned so first thing yes
it's very uncomfortable to speak about
protection and life insurance when it
comes to our continent yeah but we need
to first of all be realistic and be we
have to be realistic in our
conversations these things happen every
other day first of all it's important
that you build trust and one builds
trust through the relationship what we
do is not transactional it's not like
I'm selling a fantastic bag I've seen
these lovely earrings like the ones that
you're wearing and you know it's an
impulsive but you're like I love it and
you just bite it's tangible you like it
ours is not even tangible they're
telling you save in case something
happen to you in casee you die in casee
you get a total permanent disability we
are going to pay now here we are telling
you my dear put your money for the next
5 20 years in case a risk occurs we
shall be there for your family in case a
risk does not occur we shall still be
able to pay your claims remember first
of all our culture is very shortterm
when it comes to financial planning we
are thinking for tomorrow you know what
I
mean years exactly five years you're
like are you what are you even talking
about I'll be dead then yeah but what
people don't understand is the time goes
so
fast 5 years will come you'll get your
you'll get your claim and say I wish I'd
actually taken 10 years so it's
important that you build a relationship
what we do is is a service it is not a
product and it is intangible so when
you're dealing with things that are
tangible there has to be a form of
relationship and that relationship has
to grow which creates um which creates
confidence and credibility you cannot
buy into something that you also do not
understand so it is important that I
have walked the journey as a mother I'm
telling you all these things but do I
actually have these policies what are
the terms and conditions how am I
selling it to how am I how am I value
preposition in it to you um am I
speaking to your pain points am I
speaking to the school fees for for S1
for S6 for University so we also need to
have Clarity on our financial goals
where do you want to be in the next 5
years 6 years 10 years 15 years you say
you want to retire you told me you're 45
for example someone says they're 45 and
they want to leave the corporate the
corporate sector and going into
consultancy what does that mean the plan
yeah what's the plan because now you had
group life you had medical you were
comfortable because you're sleeping on
someone's couch remember the couch it's
is your employer now you're on your own
are you going to buy that medical plan
are you going to pay that group life but
remember you're 45 you've not even your
mileage someone who had started earlier
has a high mileage so it's important to
ascertain at what stage are they in
their life have a goal and be clear you
know you might have a goal now that you
have a goal what are the actions or what
is the plan in order to get to that
Financial goal yeah but bottom line it's
important to have that trust M
longlasting
relationship credibility MH and
integrity of the advisor and the
organization whenever you
are whenever you investing with an
organization you need to understand what
are these people's long-term goals how
long have they been in the market what
is their capitalization why do ladies
like to get men who are financially
secure because they know if anything
happens at least I have a fall back
position now when you come with
credential you know you're list
credential is listed with the stock
exchange it is highly capitalized it has
been there for since 19 I mean since
1848 and we're here for the long hold so
in case of anything you're sure yes and
all this information is actually out
there we have
Ira in case you need to find out how
many claims have been paid because
people are afraid of losing money we
work so hard for money so there's always
this fear suppose you guys leave the
market suppose there's a a sense of
bankruptcy that's looming you know
there's been a lot that's been happening
well you're safe in our hands we can
trust we're very credible we're very
solid we're very robust and we're very
liquid oo ooh ooh guys I love it and I
love how you've said even you've talked
about uh those low income earners so
that means Prudential can C to all of us
all lives matter all lives matter all
lives matter that's why we even have
Micro insurance we we have we we have
come to tell the market that what the
the misconception of thinking that
insurance is for the rich no insurance
is for every human being that has an
income and that has a financial dream
and has a fin fincial goal yeah so
there's no class ratification here we're
here for everyone guys I don't know what
more can we say please credential is
here for you all levels does not
segregate they want to secure your
future and that's what we're all
[Music]
about Gerald welcome to the show thank
you yeah so they tell me that you're the
man behind everything is that true
not really yeah well my name is Gerald
TJ the head of operations so I work with
a team of very well dedicated people
that ensure that we deliver quality
service to our clients W yes amazing
okay so just walk us through the Journey
from when someone signs up a policy
until its maturity we want to simplify
all these things for these people on the
community here yeah thanks Lisa for that
question uh this all star that's from
when you meet our financial
advisers uh they will engage you uh
identify your needs and then offer the
right solution in as far as the products
we offer are concerned yeah and uh
through that uh they will administer an
application form uh where we require you
to provide us with your details your
names your age uh beneficiary details
your preferred level of cover
and
uh identification documentation to
support your application yeah and once
we have received that uh we will rece we
will then review the information you
have provided among the questions we ask
include questions on your lifestyle M we
include questions on uh if you have had
any previous medical conditions uh we
any application for insurance in the
past yeah so that information uh we
review and then if there is Need For
more information M uh we will contact
you uh as we conclude uh the process of
confirming your cover uh in the event
that we we require you to go for
Medicals uh this is really for clients
who are taking on high levels of cover
uh we will then also guide you through
the process and take you to a facility
that we work with uh to do the medical
checkup it's free it's at company cost
and then that forms part of the basis
for the decision we make to accept your
cover so once we have accepted uh to
take you on uh to cover you and protect
you and your loved ones uh then we will
issue a policy document uh which then
details uh the level of cover that we
are granting to you
it shows who your beneficiaries are who
is covered on this policy yes so when
you talk about just to take you back a
bit the medical cover what does medical
have anything to do with life insurance
why do you need to check my Medicals so
it's it's not a medical cover uh I meant
to say that uh in some
instances we may require you to do
medical
examinations uh which then informs uh
the decision we make why is this
important uh the risk we cover uh on the
life side is a risk that is really
dependent on the life of a person so we
are looking to understand uh the state
in which you are in and at the end of
the day this also helps you to
understand your current condition and
then decide what to do going forward so
it's a two way it helps you the client
but it helps us as well uh the
underwriters to make an informed
decision such that you make we make a
decision that is Equitable in the sense
that life insurance works as a pool so
we get different lives coming into the
pool and we want to ensure that everyone
is paying the right premium for the
cover yes okay makes sense so if someone
um has a claim yes you know you given me
that policy documents I've received them
I've kept them you know and then time
comes and I need to claim it how does
Prudential ensure that it's a smooth and
effective process thanks for that
question Lisa uh Prudential is a company
that is reputable for paying claims all
valid claims and uh as a matter of fact
even in our policy documents we detail
what will be required yeah at the point
of claim and uh have provided beforehand
the documentation you will need and uh
the process that you will go through so
in the event that you have a claim uh
you can contact us through our toll-free
number uh you can also reach us on email
and our customer care team will guide
you through uh the the process until the
end and once we have received all
documentation uh you will receive your
payment within five working days only
five working days are you sure yes guys
now you know you receive your uh claim
they receive your claim and you'll have
your money because we've had some people
you know just questioning and wondering
will they actually really pay me you
know the money and what's been your
experience like uh fortunately for us uh
We've now uh operated in Uganda for over
8 years and we have uh the initial
clients we started with we have seen
their policies
mature uh for the last 4 years we've
been paying maturity Clans and I'm sure
you might have someone in your circle
who perhaps has received a maturity
payout and that goes to show how
committed credential is to honing all uh
claims okay yeah all right so I heard
somewhere in the background that uh you
know I've talked about claims but some
people may forget that they have all
these uh policies you know people
policies and forget about them I've
heard that you have people in your team
who will actually call if our policy has
expired is that true good question Lisa
again uh first of all uh thanks for
bringing it up I wanted to mention that
the contract of
insurance is one that puts an
obligation on the insurer to make to
honor the promise they make to you M
yeah now on your part you are also
required to fulfill your
obligation what is the obligation on
your on you as a client uh your
obligation is to make sure that you make
your payments timely MH uh such that
your policy does not fall off cover yeah
thank you Gerald so I would like to know
if I've had a policy with credential and
I've been paying but then for some
reason I'm not able to pay anymore for
some time is there a way prenal can help
me and I revive this policy when I'm
able what's your procedure Thank you
Lisa um credential offers a gr period on
the policies that we offer to our
clients and in the event that you unable
to pay premium for some time you will
still continue to enjoy cover but this
is for a limited period of time uh going
up to maximum 3 months wow now beyond
the third month your policy will will
lapse meaning uh you are no longer on
cover covered yeah you're no longer
covered so in case of anything PR will
not pay me any money yes and sometimes
we get uh issues like that in the public
oh I I wasn't paid we have also defined
benefits that are payable on some of our
policies yeah so in that case uh your
beneficiaries will reach out to us will
notify us uh that uh this event occurred
and then we reach out to them guide them
on the process what documentation we
need and once we have that documentation
again and have reviewed all the facts
and it's a valid claim I will make the
payment within five working days yeah I
love that and it's a tip to people out
there if you have life insurance let the
beneficiaries know so that they can
reach out to credential to actually give
them don't keep it a secret at least let
someone you know someone you trust have
the idea that you're actually insured
such that in the event that something
like this happens then your
beneficiaries don't sit back and uh
suffer in silence when actually this you
have taken on to cushion them in those
bad times yeah amazing all right so
you've talked about the phone calls that
you make let's meet the people who
actually make this phone calls all
right
[Music]
Joan M hi welcome thank you Lisa so I've
been in office and I've I've had people
have a you know a greeting like a
credential greeting can you teach me oh
yes so at credential it's always a good
morning regardless of the time of the
day so um you repeat after me so it's
good morning credential you repeat after
me and say good morning credential m uh
how you feeling today good very good
excellent oh yes oh okay let's try we
can try it out okay good morning
credential good morning how are you
feeling good very good excellent oh yes
oh yes all the time all right thank you
so much so we're talking to operations
and he mentioned that as customer care
um you help the people on board the
people and just walk them through to
ensure that they know everything that
they have signed up for so just walk us
through that process yes uh definitely
uh my name is Johan M Nami I work with
the customer care department so to Us
customer care is is not about the
service it's about the experience of a
customer with credential CU we start the
journey with a customer to the very end
which is from inception of their
policies to the maturity of their
policies so basically what is embedded
in there we try to have that connection
with our customers through the welcome
calls we try to make sure that they are
personalized as much as possible because
um our customers are very dear to us and
being in a position to reemphasize the
importance of a life insurance policy uh
from the benefits from the terms and
conditions and basically for the
self-service because we have also
digital platforms available and it's our
it's our um main purpose to make sure
that from the time of the beginning of
the policy the customer is aware of what
they're supposed to do on their Journey
uh it doesn't really stop there time and
again we check on on our customers to
make sure that uh everything is very
okay on their end to um also in times
when let's say they are missed premiums
and payments we ensure that we reach out
to the customers cuz I mean there's so
many challenges out there and what
better way to uh emphasize and have that
connection with our customers just to
understand what is going on so it's a
customer experience to us it's a journey
with our customers and we're always very
happy to serve our customers at any one
time wow amazing but I know that
credential has many clients how are you
going to make sure that you call Lisa
Cima specifically how do you do that so
um it we basically have a system that uh
tracks each and every customer that
comes in and uh we are we're such a very
big team I mean with customer experience
and we always Endeavor as much as
possible to reach out to each and every
customer cuz um much as much as um these
uh different touches have been
emphasized to you but it is very crucial
to us as a customer experience
Department to basically understand that
you know what your policy is about so
each and every customer yes Lisa is
contacted because you are very special
to us they are very special to us so
having that connection for each and
every customer is very crucial so we do
reach out to each and every customer uh
to basically understand that you are
much aware about the customer Journey
what you're supposed to do on your end
what are the terms and conditions what
are the benefits of the policy cuz at
times um you realize that at times in
our connections at times those benefits
are not even resounded or re-echoed for
them to know that it's helping to get
the best out of life plan for their
future plan for um retirement plan for
it's just like having a financial goal
but we are there to walk you through it
to make you understand basically the
basics that you need along the journey
okay someone may be out there and you've
touched on the benefits of you know of
this thing just break it down for us in
simple terms what are the benefits of
having these kinds of policies so the
benefits of uh having a life insurance
policy uh just basically uh goes back to
uh having dreams having goals it could
be a family you have you're basically
planning on how how best are you going
to make sure that your family has the
best let's say in 5 years in 10 years to
come uh it's very um important to note
that um along the journey we are not
aware of what is going to happen are you
aware about what is going to happen
tomorrow no uh live examples we have uh
examples of covid we have I think I
think each and every household was
impacted in one way all the other how
prepared are you in times like that so
life insurance policies are there to
remind us of that to be prepared at any
one point so part of the benefit that
comes with a policy is that protection
that is given to a policy holder um in a
policy holder is basically the life
assured the life that is protected
making sure that God forbid if anything
happens along the journey in case of
total permanent disability in case of
death we also have products that cover
critical illnesses um we've seen
critical illnesses uh we have cancers we
have uh Kaden failures we have heart
conditions so there are products that
really are are tailored to ker for such
conditions so in case it happens along
the journey uh we know that if a policy
holder is still on cover you are
eligible to access that payout ex claim
so being prepared for uncertainities is
very crucial and uh also the icing on a
on a on a on a life insurance policy is
when you reach maturity yeah there's
something else I want to ask yes someone
has a policy with credential okay and
maybe I've signed up for 7 years okay
but then after 2 years I'm like no me I
want to end and can I get all my money
what happens okay um so being able to
understand what life insurance means it
means it's a it's a longterm it's a
long-term process it's not a shortterm
so at the very beginning of the policies
uh what customer experience does is to
reemphasize that the policy you've taken
up is basically a longterm policy and
it's also very uh important to not that
uh we do understand there could be
challenges along the journey that is
where as as customer care we come in to
make sure we have uh that different and
also make sure that we have that touch
with you along the journey so as to
understand if there are challenges but
it doesn't mean that uh if you fail
along the way you are definitely losing
out on your policy cuz the minimum
expectation on on your policy the
minimum payment should be a payment of 3
years but cash in it out should be at
the end of the policy so that means at
the end of the at the end of the seven
years or at the end of the 5 years
should you have met a minimum of
payments in 3 years you would still
qualify to be paid out with all the
bonuses aced along the journey so it
doesn't necessarily mean that if I've
not been able to finish the entire
period of the policy I will be losing
out no for as long as you've made a
minimum payment on your policy of 3
years you eligible to cash it out at the
maturity of the policy but it also URS
bonuses along the way so you cannot cash
out uh before the agreed contractual um
term of the policy but you are able to
at least consistently pay for a minimum
of 3 years so that you're able to enjoy
the maturity benefit and uh also as you
pay for the minimum of the 3 years you
your life is still on cover yeah and we
make sure that uh your life is still on
cover for as long as the premiums have
been paid for a minimum of 3 years okay
so I just want to make sure I'm
understanding yes after 3 years yes my
my my term was let's say s years yes
pleas but I've been paying consistently
for 3 years pleas anything below 3 years
I can't get money yes anything 3 years
you can't below 3 years okay then after
3 years and I want to opt out I can
still opt out after Mone so after 3
years you can opt out we call it
surrender but we don't usually uh we
don't usually encourage that now number
one because we believe the reason or
part of the reasons that you might have
had for for the policy or the reason
that's why you chose the five or seven
years was simply because you had a
financial goal you had a dream so um
when you do try to terminate your policy
before the actual um before the actual
um
date definitely it's going to affect you
uh so surrender is more of you are
basically ending your contract before
it's more like a breach of a contract so
surrender comes at a penalty okay let
them know what the penalty is surrender
comes at a penalty basically it's more
of you get less of what you have
contributed so even during uh such times
we try to as customer experience it is
our to reemphasize that and also to let
you know about the other option which is
paid up the one I've talked about where
you are at least able to pay for a
minimum of three years but opt to reach
the maturity of your policy as opposed
to getting a penalty yes so we always
try to make sure even our policy
documents uh we make sure that that
information is embedded in there and uh
we also do try to reemphasize in case of
anything that
a client may not be able to understand
cuz I mean the insurance language at
times yes so at any one point our
customers can always call us uh via our
customer care uh numbers or they can
always email us uh so that we are able
to serve them and we're able to
basically um serve them better to
understand how best they can go about
their policies as opposed to uh being
out there and you don't know what
exactly is supposed to be done with your
policy okay I love that so I heard that
credential has an app I'm a client of
credential so I have the app maybe just
let them know what the app really does
amazing do I still need to call you how
does it work so um we all must agree
postco the world has gone digital and
what better way for a customer or for a
policy holder to have um to have that
self-service as of when you need it
accessing Cent Port you can easily
access your statements as a customer um
get receipts via um uh via the client
portal so it's a bit sophisticated uh
but very easy to understand we make sure
that all the details that you might need
about your policy are embedded in there
so um there is a link we often give out
to our customers that is of course
during the welcome call and at times we
also make sure that we take you through
the steps you you must follow but it's
easy it's very easy there is a link we
send it to you you just follow the steps
on how to sign up as long as you have
your policy number you have your phone
number just put your phone number create
a password and you sign up to access
your premium statements and uh and
receipts so also with a client portal it
helps you uh to easily uh create or
reach out to the customer care um uh to
to the customer care team
so there is uh uh uh basically designed
to for you to be able to reach out to
credential as fast as possible but most
importantly the client portal is it
helps you have that confidence with how
your policy is running um you're able to
see how your premiums are flowing on
your statement the receipts so yes
that's all about the client portal do
you have the client portal yes I do I
love it first of all I love that you
send mails after I've paid so that I'm
able to see the receipt and then just to
keep checking you know after sometimes
you've paid you you don't really
remember when did I last pay you're able
to just track so I really love that if I
want to just check if I'm on track the
app is really helping me definitely so
that's amazing okay so thank you for
sharing with us guys you've heard from
customer care they're really into
building the relationship between
credential and us the client isn't that
amazing I really love that that you call
us you know and make sure that we don't
forget that our policies are mature in
ETC so yes from the CEO to customer care
it's clear that credential is not just
an insurance company it's a community
dedicated to securing your future so
reach out to them using the numbers on
the screen and start your journey
[Music]
today